

ADILAH BINTI ZAKARIA

1732, Jln 18/43 Taman Sri Serdang, 43400 Serdang, Selangor | 014-8294418 | adilah1690@gmail.com | 27 Years Old

Objective

I am really interested in food science and technology and want to challenge myself in this industry. I am also want to contribute my skills and effort to the company and do not mind to start from the bottom in other to gain experiences.

Experience

Admin Officer (Contract) | IOI Group, Putrajaya | Oct 2016- Present

- · Manage and record company annual report request
- · Manage ESOS system for IOI employee
- Assist in preparing documents for Director Board Meeting and Annual General Meeting for shareholders
- · Record and filing documents for IOI properties and IOI Corporation

Research Assistant | Faculty Food Science and Technology| Universiti Putra Malaysia | May 2014- April 2016

· Assist lecturer in food research

Intern Research Trainee | Institute of Halal Products, Serdang | Mac 2012- Aug 2012

- · Conducted research project given f especially in food halal
- · Learn used various instruments for food analysis such as GC, HPLC, FTIR, DSC and others

Education

Master of Science | Nov 2016 | Universiti Putra Malaysia

- · Major: Food Technology (by research)
- · CGPA: 3.875

Bachelor of Food Science with Honors | Nov 2013 | Universiti Malaysia Sabah

- · Major: Food Technology and Bioprocess
- · CGPA: 2.96

SPM | DEC 2007 | SMKA Sheikh Abdul Malek

- · Major: Science Stream
- · Result: 6A 5B

Skills & Abilities

Food Analysis

 Experience in conducting food analysis such as carbohydrate, protein, moisture content, water activity, fat and others during degree level and master programed level

Fats and Oil Analysis

 Conducted fats and oil analysis before in degree thesis and master thesis

Chromatography Analysis

 Conducted lab work using using Gas Chromatography and High Performance Liquid Chromatography

Statistical Analysis

 Knowledgeable in using software statistical analysis such as Minitab and SPSS

Microsoft office

 Good skills in Microsoft office software such as Words, Power Point and Excel

Management Works

 Able to work in team work and independently for the tasks given although in under pressure and limited time given.

Language

English

Written: 8/10Spoken: 7/10

Malay

Written: 9/10Spoken: 10/10

Thesis/Paperwork/Research

Thesis

- Effects of different frying methods, frying conditions and pre-treatments on formation of aldehydes in French fries
- · A study of fats and oils sources in puff pastry around Kota Kinabalu, Sabah
- · Changes in quality and aldehydes content of frying oil and French fries using different frying methods
- · Effect of pre-treatments process on reduction of aldehyde, texture and sensory attributes of French fries
- · Analysis of the spectra of fats and oils using Fourier Transform Infrared (FTIR) Spectroscopy.
- · Profiling fatty acids in fat and oil pastry using Gas Chromatography Ion Flame Detector (GC-FID)
- · Profiling alcohol beverages using e-Nose instrument.
- · Identification alcohol contents in local food using GC-FID

Achievements/Involvements

- Librarian, SMKA Sheikh Abdul Malek, 2006-2007
- Attend Taekwondo competition, Level Kuala Terengganu Zone, 2006
- · Involve National Service Programmed, 2008
- A member Malaysian Red Crescent Society, National Level, 2008
- Involve Kembara Programmed in 2 semester, Universiti Malaysia Sabah, 2009-2010

- Committee of Food Service at Universiti Malaysia Sabah Convocation, 2010
- · Attend Halal Selangor Halal Seminar, 2012
- Participated in exhibition and competition of food development from ADABI, 2012
- Attend Statistics Workshop in Universiti Putra Malaysia, 2014

References

Associate Professor Dr. Seyed Hamed Mirhosseini

- · Lecturer Universiti Putra Malaysia
- · 03-89468390

Associate Professor Dr. Hasmadi Mamat

- · Lecturer Universiti Malaysia Sabah
- · 019-5753575

Vincent Tan

- · IOI Company Secretary
- · 03 89478888